Hey guys, and welcome to a different space and fiction maybe most of them most of them
will be a new to this topic, Hooking and Unhooking maybe some of them shared or set
term of Hooking. We will be we will be use Hooks word in multiple times even fish when
we will be going for fishing in harbor or something. But in cyber security time it will be
like pretty different like the Hooking part. Let me show you what was the hooking. Basically
the hooking is used by the EDRs antivirus softwares as well as the threat factors. Both the
terms like the hooking method will be used by protectors to develop their malware to evade the
EDRs and antivirus platforms as well as the different a different schools like EDRs and
antivirus softwares or whatever. So, the basically the hooking was introduced by introduced for
programmers. So, let us take an example. There is there is a programmer who developed an
application and he left that organization and so a new developer has been joined and the
new developer was unable to see the code. So, what was the code he was used and how he
returned the program and how he quoted the application. He does not know what was going on inside
because the code was not visible. So, at this time he needs to use some updates. He needs to
change some options or he needs to add some options in the program. So, for that, we can use a
hooking. Basically, hooking will change the execution flow of the program and let us, I will give
you a small example. So, you are playing some game and your health is important there. There was a
fighting game and so your health will be, if the health will be 100 you can fight more but when the
health will be reduced to less than 10, you have a lesser time to fight right. So, what we can do,
we can hoop the game and we can change the execution flow. So, whenever you hit by an target,
whenever you hit by some gun or sniper or something, till you will be having 100 percent
of your health. So, you hit multiple times like even 100,000 times. So, still you will be having
a full percentage of health to fight against your target. So, what we did, we just
changed, we just given small modification in a program. It started as a hooking, we just
modified the execution flow of the program and we just modified the health to 100.
So, whenever we did some kind of hooking in a gaming applications to change the health
to make a consistent health, like 100 percentage, you can continuously play the gaming.
So, this is called as the game hacking or something. So, by the method of hooking, you can
easily achieve that. The same way in cybersecurity, the difference aviation tactics,
the difference aviation programs, it will be doing some APA level hooking to hide from
antivirus softwares or EDRs programs. So, let me give a small example of how the hooking
will be worse in the real time. So, I have a bit different of antivirus program in my machine,
so you can see here and let me go for a task post. So, here you can see the application,
task post-30XE and here you can see the handles, dealers, threads has been loaded. So, if you see this
DLL, DTHKM64.DLL, a bit different of hooking DLL. So, it was involved in the process, right,
it was involved in the task post-DrdXE process. Why? The bit different are involving in task
post-DrdXE. What? The bit different are doing here. So, let me give a brief explanation.
So, let us take an example. I was developing a program, a malicious code, so that code will be going
to inject a malicious cell code into the task post-DrdXE. So, whenever we tries to inject
our malicious code into the task post-DrdXE, so what we will be doing? We will be calling some kind
of APA functions, right, like virtual log of right process memory of create remote thread of,
okay. So, EDR will be monitoring this APA functions and it will be stopping us, right. So,
in the backend, EDR monitoring the process, right, EDR is EDR monitoring the process.
How EDR monitoring the process? How EDR knows? Our malicious program is going to inject something
into the task post-DrdXE. How EDR knows? How EDR understand what was going in the background of the
process, okay. So, the hooking is coming into play, okay. So, the anti-virus software, food, some
DLLs into the application task post-DrdXE and it was completely monitoring the process,
okay. So, now the EDR know what was going inside the process, what was the IP communication going on,
what is the DLLs calling, what is the APA functions calls are going on,
what was the system calls going on, everything EDR come to know the entire process, the backbone
of entire process, okay. So, by the hooking technique, the EDR can completely monitor the process
including the APIs, IT communications, contents, code, et cetera, okay. So, now I already said,
so, EDR will be one of a powerful tool, it will be, it has a capability to do anything
inside Windows, it can hook any kind of process, okay. So, in our example, we just see in the
task post-DrdXD, that was hooked by the bid defender hooking DLL process, okay.
So, whenever the Windows, Windows boots up, the bid defender loads DLL file by calling
load library of DLL and hook the DLL inside the task post-DrdXE, okay. By this,
so, whatever the application was doing, the EDR comes to know, the EDR and if a software
comes to know what was happening inside the process, okay. So, now I hope you have a clear
understanding about the hooking, so what was hooking and how the EDR and the EDR software still
hook, okay. Let's take an example of real world, how the malware is going to be react and how the
EDR will be reacting. Let me, you, you very brief explanation how it will be happening, okay,
in the subo example, the subar example, okay. So, let's take an example of
our day-to-day activities in the home, okay. Not a, not a home, let's take an example of
example of a store and so the restaurant has a kitchen, right. So, inside the kitchen, everything
has been performed, right. The cooking, the cleaning, managing everything, right. So, the kitchen,
okay. So, the next part of the kitchen will be the headstop, okay. One of the headships
is commanding what needs to be done head, the head chef, who will be coming and next part will be the
waiter, okay. She will be, so we are the customers and we'll be ordering to the waiter, right.
I need a piece of it more cheese or more chicken, that you can need some tomato, onion or whatever,
right. So, we'll be calling the waiter and we'll be ordering and we are the customers, right.
So, this is, okay. So, let's take an example, the kitchen of a kernel in our machine,
okay. We will be calling the kitchen of a sub kernel and the head chef of the NTDLL,
so we know what is a NTDLL, right. NTDLL. This is a DL file which holds an important AP functions,
which will be which will be used by windows, okay. And we can call the waiter as the kernel,
kernel32dLL, sorry I was taking some time, I was drawing in the Hpad, okay.
Okay. And the human of application, okay.
You can call the application as a Chrome task host or whatever, okay.
So, let's take an example here, okay. So, our program,
chilling to the waiter, okay. Our program, telling to the kernel32dLL, like I want to save a file,
I need to save a file, okay. So, you are downloading something from a Chrome and the file needs
to be saved in download folder. So, your Chrome calling, I want to save a file, okay.
And it was telling to the kernel dot DL, okay. So, it's not a kernel, kernel32, okay.
Let me take that kernel32dLL. And what the next step, so your kernel32 dot DLLL calling
the Hpad self, okay. The NTDLL, and it was telling the application needs to save some file, okay.
So, what the Hpad self will be doing? The Hpad self will be calling the sys call, okay.
Direct sys call, and he will be reaching out to the kernel, and the Hpad self, the NTDLL will be
saying to the kernel, like the application needs to save some file, please allocate some space and
help them, okay. So, the kitchen directly got the order and he is cooking. The same way,
your application commanding to, I want to save a file to kernel32dLL, and your kernel32dLL
reaching out to the NTDLL, the lower AP function, it's a high level AP, the kernel32dLL
was a higher level, and it was calling to the lower level AP function, the Hpad self, and there
was NTDLL, and NTDLL dot DLLL, giving a sys call to the system call to the kernel,
and saying the application needs to save some file, we need to do some help there, okay.
So, whenever you need to interact with the hardware, so you were saving the files to the hardware
side, or hottest, that was a physical pause in our laptop, right. So, if you want to interact with
the hardware, the operating system, the windows will not have a capability to do that, okay.
So, only the kernel can able to communicate with the hardware as well as the operating system,
okay. It was, it was, it was, it has an intermediate, it was an intermediate for the hardware,
as well as the windows operating system, okay. So, the kernel only can able to allocate
some memory inside the hardware, okay. The same thing happening here.
So, the kernel, like the kernel, when the, when the heads of the NTDLL dot DL call the sys call,
so the kernel goes to the hard drive, and he, and it was doing, and it was,
giving some space to save the file, okay. So, only the NTDLL dot DLLL
can only call the sys call, so the kernel will be only responsible for sys calls, okay.
Only it was, only it was, communicate through the sys call, okay.
So, the kernel only need a sys call for a communication, so to allocate a space to do anything,
okay. So, this is the entire worry, what will this happen? So, once you, once you call anything
inside the program, even in node path, you are writing something or anything, okay.
So, let's take a real-time example. So, there is a, there is a node path, and there was an
application, and the node path was calling the right file of APA function, it was going to the
writer, okay. And it needs to write some file, and to what the kernel was doing,
so it was calling the AP function, W write, write file, okay.
Write file of, and the beta going with the H of, and he's saying, this node path needs to
save some file, okay. So, suddenly the APA, so this all the higher level APA is, okay, write file out, okay.
And the entity LL, so once it reaches to entity LL, so the APA will be changed to the lower, lower level
of APA, okay, it will be adding NT, native, write file out, okay. So, nothing gets changed, only the
APA functions will be changed, so this all the lower level APA functions, so this all the lower level
APA is, okay. So, this is the higher level, write file off, and the NT, DLL was a lower level APA,
okay. And once the lower level APA gets called, so the next part will be the syscals,
okay, the syscals will be calling and it will reach now to the panel, okay. So, this is the
entire cycle of, of cooking, okay. So, in our scenario, what our bit different software did,
okay. So, our area, our area, and the various software, it will be creating
God, it will be acting as a God after the kitchen, okay. So, it will be the, the, the,
the area will be staying here, or AV, and the various software will be staying here,
and it will be watching what was happening in the back end. So, what APA was calling,
so what was going and what needs to be, what needs to be saved in the download folder,
what needs to be right in the memory or anything. So, it will be watching everything,
okay. It will be cooking, and it will be watching age and everything, okay.
Now, let us see which function, which APA function area, who, okay. The EDR, who, the lower level APA
function, NT write-off, right. So, it, who, the NT write-off APA functions and watching what
was happening in the programs, right. Because it was inter mediator for the heads-off,
and it was inter mediator between the kitchen and the heads-up, okay. So, in between on AP,
if going to be called, the NT write-off function, there was a, there was a helping assist call,
and this needs to be called. So, okay. So, the EDR, understand each and everything, it was
who, the NT write-off APA functions, right. So, it, who.
So, now, let us take a, let us take a real time example, let me show you something.
Let me open a node pad here, so act, and I can explain for what will be,
what will be done. Let me open, what, what is actually a cooking, okay. Let me open a X64 debug,
and let me attach the node pad here, and let me go for a memory map, and let me redirect to the,
text for minute text resource. Yeah, follow in disassembler,
and here you can see, here you can see the bytes 40 is 255,
and the text section was pointing towards this BCE,000, let me open a process hacker,
and let me go to the node pad here, load the node pad, and let me search for node pad.exe. So,
here you can find the same address, the 75 BCE,000, right BCE,000, let me expand this, okay.
So, here you can see the same memory functions, right, same bytes, 40 is 255, then
8d, second, sorry for the previous, previous one because I already set up break point there. So, now,
you can see the 40 is 255, and the next byte was 48 AD, 60, 24 C9, right. So, you can see the
40, 55, 45, 45, 48, 48 AD, 60, okay. So, what I am going to do,
I was sitting up break point, okay, break point, so now the break point has been set towards this
address, and so what we are going to do, we are going to move this, okay. So, we are going to change
the execution flow of that, flow of this program, okay. Let me go to the process hacker,
and let me give a rewrite, rewrite. So, now you can see the bytes has been changed, 40, 55,
and CC. So, previously it was in the 40, 48, right. So, now we can see the CC has been involved,
right. But in before it was of 48, before I set to the break point, before I set in a break point,
it was in the 48, now it was CC. We just changed execution flow, right,
of the program. So, now, so if I execute, if I execute this program,
so what the program will do, it will be redirecting to the debugger, right, because I set a break
point there, right. It will be stopping there, okay. There is a break point, so the program execution
will be stopped, and it will be waiting for a next command from a debugger, okay. So, this is called
as the hooking. We just changed the execution flow, right. So, we just talked to the programs
from the execution by setting a break point. The address has been changed to CC,
the bytes have been changed instead of 48, here you can find the CC. After 40, 55, 48 will be there,
but now there is a CC. So, now you can see the execution flow has been changed.
Now, the flow is redirecting to the debugger, so now you can, now you can feel how hooking will
be, how hooks will be opened, okay. So, this is how the EDRs and EDRs and anti-verse software
should be hooking, and it will be monitoring for what we are doing in the application, okay.
So, now, let's see how we can bypass the anti-verse software using the hooking method, okay.
Let's go to the draw and take an example. Let me erase this, give me a sec.
Now, let's take an example about how we need to develop our programs here, okay.
So, there is some malicious application, you are developing this malicious app, malapp,
so mal.exe, okay.
So, once you, once you call in any kind of API function, like kernel 32-based functions,
like write file off, so your mal.exe will be going to write a ransom node, read me.txt or something,
okay. So, your kernel 32.DRL will be calling write file off function, right.
Right file of function, but once the write file off function get called through the kernel 32.DRL,
so the, it will be redirecting towards the heads of anti-DRL, the function named anti-write off.
So, the important thing we need to monitor, the EDR will be hooked, the anti-write off functions,
okay. So, now, whenever your program calls the anti-write off functions, EDR knows what was going
inside the background, it was completely monitoring what was going inside the background, okay.
So, whenever your program calls the, your mal.exe calls the anti-write off function,
so the EDR coming into play, and it was watching what was going inside the program, okay.
It can, it to have a couple of videos stop, terminate your process, even it can do anything, okay.
So, now what we can do, we need to bypass this step, right. We need to bypass this step.
Instead of calling anti-write off the lower level AP functions, so what our program needs to do,
it needs to, it needs to directly call the syscall, okay. Through the syscall number, for example,
the syscall number of anti-write off function will be 0x65, this was by it, okay.
Let's call this was a syscall number of anti-write off function, so our program needs to
call the 0x55, and it needs to reach out to the kernel. Instead of calling a function AP function,
you needs to call a syscall number, okay. So, by calling the syscall number, you can easily bypass
EDR by EDR, okay. So, now the EDR doesn't know what was going inside, what was happening inside of the program, okay.
So, you will be reading a syscall, how you got to know what was a syscall number, okay.
So, whenever you started running the application, okay, for application, you need to collect a syscall address,
okay. So, the syscall address will be hiding inside the anti-reall dot-reall function,
so you need to read a syscall from anti-reall dot-reall functions whenever you
whenever you started executing the, whenever your program was in the execution mode, okay.
So, that will be the only method you can
you can easily bypass the EDR, okay. So, this will be the only step.
I hope you have, you have understood explanation about the hooking, so how it will be happening,
okay. So, the last instead of calling the APA function directly, we can use a syscall number,
0-X-5-5 and we can, it's an example, 0-X-5-5 and we can call the kernel. So, this is the,
you can easily bypass the EDRs without monitoring what you are doing, okay.
So, you need to read the syscall number whenever your program was in the runtime
and you need to call the syscall number and you can that are very short to the kernel,
instead of calling the lower level APA function, okay. So, I hope you have enjoyed this video
and we can see you guys in the next video. Bye-bye.